# Edward Nnaemeka Ugwu

Frontend Developer +2348164578471 Nnvedward@gmail.com https://nnvemeka.vercel.app Enugu, Nigeria

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An experienced front-end engineer with demonstrated expertise in React, Next, Angular, JavaScript and Typescript, I specialize in developing responsive websites and web applications that provide a beautiful, intuitive user experience and drive maximum engagement and conversions. I have a keen eye for detail and have successfully applied my skills to the financial, e-commerce, and health care industries. With a passion for creating top-notch user experiences, I take immense pride in my work, continually pursuing excellence while closely aligning with product objectives.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Software Engineering: Performance optimization, Design, Implementation, Responsive design,

Cross-browser compatibility, Testing, Maintenance, Debugging, Requirement analysis.

**Programming Languages:** Typescript and JavaScript. **Frameworks & Libraries:** ReactJS, NextJS and Angular.

**UI Component Libraries:** Chakra UI, Material UI and Bootstrap. **Styling:** CSS, Sass/SCSS, Styled components and Tailwind CSS.

**Queries:** Fetch API, Axios, GraphQL and React query. **Animations**: Framer motion and GSAP(Greensock).

Version Control: GIT.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### Frontend Engineer – Freexit Technologies(Part Time) [Lagos]

Feb. 2023 - Current

- Spearheaded the frontend development team in architecting and implementing a cuttingedge logistics software platform.
- Leveraged Nextjs to create a highly responsive and user-friendly interface for our logistics service, ensuring an exceptional user experience.
- Implemented robust security measures to safeguard customer data and financial transactions, ensuring the safety and trust of our users.
- Led efforts to enhance the platform's scalability, performance, and reliability to meet the demands of a growing user base.
- Fostered a culture of innovation, encouraging team members to explore and implement new technologies and features that enhance the service.

- Made recommendations for new technology integration based on suitability and alignment to business goals, resulting to 35% increase in efficiency.
- Designed and optimized responsive user interfaces, enabling seamless access to critical patient data and clinical decision support on various devices.
- Collaborated with backend developers to establish efficient data communication and integration, enabling real-time access to patient records and clinical insights.
- Teamed up to implement user-centric design strategy, translating UX and business requirements into coded solutions, improving overall user satisfaction by 20%.
- Implemented stringent security measures to ensure compliance with healthcare data regulations, safeguarding patient information and privacy.

## Software Developer – Bluetag Technologies(Full Time) [Enugu]

Jul. 2022 - Nov. 2022

- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality by 20%.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Integrated constructive programs into cohesive product.
- Designed intuitive graphical user interfaces to improve user experience.
- Integrated software components into fully functional software system.

## Frontend Developer – Kellispay (Contract) [Lagos]

Jan. 2022 - Jun. 2022

- Planned and developed interfaces that simplified overall management and ease usage.
- Optimized website and increased speed by 15%.
- Built and deployed scalable mobile responsive User Interfaces for maximized User experience.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.

#### Frontend Developer – Davayte(Contract) [Kazan]

Jan. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- Worked cooperatively with client services, sales and design team in deadline-driven environment.
- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements, increasing app speed by 10%.
- Coded using HTML, CSS and JavaScript to develop features for both mobile and desktop platforms.
- Improved tools to boost user interaction and deliver design versatility.

#### **Software Developer – Nigerian Breweries PLC(IT) [Lagos]**

April. 2018 - Sept. 2018

- Built and deployed scalable mobile responsive User Interfaces for maximized User experience.
- Assisted with search engine optimization (SEO) strategies and techniques.
- Maintained existing wordpress websites, ensuring their continued functionality and performance.
- Wrote well designed, testable and efficient code.

Participated in code reviews to ensure best practices.

#### **PROJECTS**

• Project Name: School Motive.

**Description:** Developed a comprehensive school management system to enhance personalized learning experiences, streamline administrative tasks, and improve communication between educators, students, and parents. Utilized cutting-edge technologies to create an intuitive and user-friendly platform for the digital age.

Technologies: React, Typescript, Tanstack query, Chakra Ul.

Link: https://dev.schoolmotive.com

Project Name: MezGPT.

**Description**: Created MezGPT, an AI tool revolutionizing open-source project data management. MezGPT optimizes data handling for collaborative software development, enhancing efficiency and effectiveness across industries.

Technologies: NextJS, Typescript, Wagmi, RainbowKit.

Link: MezGPT

Project Name: Nogabi.

**Description**: Nogabi is a software development agency that offers robust, secure, and scalable solutions, from collaborative ideation and product strategy to engineering, testing, and continuous scaling.

**Technologies**: React, Typescript, Framer motion.

Link: https://nogabi-solutions.com

## **EDUCATION**

Enugu State University of Science and Technology, Enugu.
Bachelor Of Science in Computer Science

Sept. 2015 – Oct. 2019

#### CERTIFICATIONS

Meta: Advanced React
Dec. 2022